<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>speaking.io</title>
 <link href="http://speaking.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://speaking.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-02-10T11:22:52-08:00</updated>
 <id>http://speaking.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>speaking.io</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Using Images</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/design/using-images"/>
   <updated>2014-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/design/using-images</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey which likeness of Winston Churchill inspires you to weather out a bombing
run more? This one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/1W2V2O411i2Q/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;or this one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  o   - HEY IM WINSTON CHURTCHIL
 /|\
 / \
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to guess, you either picked the first one, because it is a vibrant
image full of evocative character and unbroken will, or you picked the second
one because you are a jerk and just wanted to mess up my example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say is that even more than plain text, images can really make
things pop for your audience (unless they&amp;rsquo;re all jerks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Finding a photo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really like photos. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to describe why I like them so much, but I came
up with a phrase that sums it up pretty well: a picture is worth a hundred
million words. Photos can capture attention and interest quickly and without
much effort, so you might want to include them in your slide deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I&amp;rsquo;m designing something that needs a good photo, more often than not I&amp;rsquo;ll
toss one of &lt;a href=&quot;http://photos.zachholman.com&quot;&gt;my photos&lt;/a&gt; in the slide. It can be
fun to chat with people about certain photos they might notice in the deck and
be able to say &amp;ldquo;yeah, I took that&amp;rdquo;. If you&amp;rsquo;re at all into photography, give that
a shot. You&amp;rsquo;d be surprised at how good even cell phone photos can look these
days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not a photog by any stretch of the imagination, there are plenty of
places you can find royalty-free photos online. Flickr has a great &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/creativecommons/&quot;&gt;Creative
Commons&lt;/a&gt; search, and even Google Images&#39;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/advanced_image_search?as_st=y&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_epq=&amp;amp;as_oq=&amp;amp;as_eq=&amp;amp;cr=&amp;amp;as_sitesearch=&amp;amp;safe=images&amp;amp;q=arby&#39;s+roast+beef+sandwich&amp;amp;tbs=sur:f&amp;amp;tbm=isch&quot;&gt;advanced search&lt;/a&gt;
has a nice &amp;ldquo;usage rights&amp;rdquo; section you can filter by.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Using a photo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a (preferably big, high-quality) photo, toss it in your slide
deck. But for the love of god, don&amp;rsquo;t do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/0A1g3s0C450E/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, keep things as simple and as &lt;em&gt;big as possible&lt;/em&gt;. Blow it up to the whole
slide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/0C0n2x0N3009/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with text&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that last screenshot, I used a couple quick tricks to make the text more
legible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Play with levels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one, I turned the exposure down. You can do this either in a different
program or, in this example I just did it directly in Keynote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/2T060O0F0y3c/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, it makes the whole photo darker. It might make the photo as a whole a
little harder to make out, but your focus is on the legibility of your slide
deck, not photorealistic renderings of some random photo you have up on screen
for four seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Put another backdrop under the text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually playing with the levels of the photo is fine, but in the Churchill shot
I had a harder time placing the brighter pink text over a lighter grey
background. So, I cheated. I added a black rectangle behind the text:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/3y1n1M1d450r/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a full black; it&amp;rsquo;s at about 70% opacity, so some of the background
bleeds through, which I think is a nice enough effect. I just wanted that
slightly darker so the text would pop more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use drop shadows for the same type of effect as well: just make them
offset by 0px and don&amp;rsquo;t blur the shadows too much, otherwise you start to lose
the effect some.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Finding Where to Talk</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/plan/finding-a-talk"/>
   <updated>2014-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/plan/finding-a-talk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s society, you can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;just give a talk&lt;/em&gt;. By that I mean you can&amp;rsquo;t just
stand up on your bus ride into work and start blabbing about whatever you want
to talk about. By that I mean you will probably get arrested, because you will
Stick Out, and society doesn&amp;rsquo;t like People That Stick Out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, try knocking out the bus driver, stealing the bus, and driving it to a
secluded section of the woods. Then it becomes a private gathering and it is
okay to talk to the passengers at great lengths because you have stolen their
only means of transportation away from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barring your desire to acquire another felony on your record, you might want to
try another couple of options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Finding a meetup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never spoken before? If you&amp;rsquo;re in the tech industry, you might want to try your
local meetup groups. This is great for a few reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smaller&lt;/em&gt;. Compared to a conference, meetups are typically much smaller and
shorter in duration. Might ease your nerves a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Friendlier&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s your local community! They&amp;rsquo;re probably not jerks, otherwise
they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be living in your nice cozy town! Meetups are usually nice places to get your toes wet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com&quot;&gt;Meetup.com&lt;/a&gt; is probably your best bet in finding meetup
groups in your area. At some point, try talking to the organizer and offering to
share your knowledge. (You might want to go for a few months first so you can
meet people and get to know the meetup group. Strangers are just friends you
haven&amp;rsquo;t met yet!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Finding a conference&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conferences are a lot of fun, particularly if they&amp;rsquo;re in distant, romantic
cities (or Detroit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not sure which conference you&amp;rsquo;re interested in? Check out
&lt;a href=&quot;http://lanyrd.com&quot;&gt;Lanyrd&lt;/a&gt; — it&amp;rsquo;s got the best assortment of conferences out
there. Once you find an upcoming conference that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in, you&amp;rsquo;ll
probably want to &lt;a href=&quot;http://speaking.io/plan/writing-a-cfp/&quot;&gt;fill out a CFP (Call for Papers)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t get accepted at the conference of your choice? That&amp;rsquo;s great, because many
conferences will do &lt;em&gt;lightning talks&lt;/em&gt;, which are short five-minute hard-limit
talks by anyone in the audience. Giving a lightning talk is a &lt;em&gt;fantastic&lt;/em&gt; way to
get started with public speaking. Even if you freeze up and the whole thing is a
disaster, it&amp;rsquo;s only five minutes long and people are sort of expecting failure
anyway (most lightning talks are conceived, created, and delivered the same
day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Other resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of interesting opportunities out there beyond just conferences
and meetups, too. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few good resources that&amp;rsquo;ll help you get started:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For women in tech: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/callbackwomen&quot;&gt;@callbackwomen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. A
slew of tweets from programming conferences looking for women (and everyone!)
to talk at their event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For everybody: &lt;a href=&quot;http://lanyrd.com/calls/&quot;&gt;Lanyrd&amp;rsquo;s CFP section&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Probably
the most definitive list you&amp;rsquo;ll see.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(If you know any more, please &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:&amp;#122;&amp;#97;&amp;#99;&amp;#104;&amp;#64;&amp;#122;&amp;#97;&amp;#99;&amp;#104;&amp;#104;&amp;#111;&amp;#108;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#110;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;shoot me an email&lt;/a&gt;
and I&amp;rsquo;d love to get it listed here.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Duplicating Objects</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/design/duplicating-objects"/>
   <updated>2014-02-10T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/design/duplicating-objects</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Have you ever seen &lt;em&gt;The Fly&lt;/em&gt; starring Jeff Goldblum?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/281S1y063g2p/goldblum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically Goldblum — the kooky mad scientist he is — invents a teleportation
device, but when he tries it on himself, a housefly sneaks into the machine with
him and Goldblum comes out the other end half-fly, half-Goldblum. Definitely
should have won a Grammy, but the point I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make here is that Goldblum
probably would have been better off duplicating himself instead of mixing his
DNA up with some lameazoid insect. Had that happened, we would have had ended up
with &lt;em&gt;two&lt;/em&gt; Jeff Goldblums and the world would have been noticeably better off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Quickly building things up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Keynote, I use &lt;code&gt;⌘D&lt;/code&gt; religiously. That&amp;rsquo;ll duplicate whatever you have
selected: slides, objects, text, groups of slides, groups of groups of text,
small rodents, whatever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s kind of amazing how much time this saves me. I feel weird writing about it
because there&amp;rsquo;s nothing special about it: I&amp;rsquo;m just duplicating shit. But when
you&amp;rsquo;re dealing with text styles and specific font settings and colors, it makes
a ton more sense to just grab what you need and bring it over to a new slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The scratchpad slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way I leverage duping quickly is to build a scratchpad slide at the start of
my slide deck. It has big chunks of things I might use later in the deck. Here&amp;rsquo;s
a quick example of one:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/241G3C3o0L3G/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delete this slide before you give your talk, of course. It&amp;rsquo;s just there for you
quickly copy styles back and forth between slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also use Master Slides for purpose- basically you set up one overall
style in your Master Slide and you can change all the rest of them from that one
spot. Personally I tend to make each slide a bit unique, so I don&amp;rsquo;t use Master
Slides all too often.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Advanced: The no-shift&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure I&amp;rsquo;m the only one who notices this in the entire planet, but it&amp;rsquo;s
something virtually everyone messes up. Fixing it makes for a more pleasant
slide deck overall, so this might be interesting to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine you have this slide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/1C2133113o2D/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then you build this slide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/0g2j3p3l3K2Y/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does that bother you much? Probably not, because we&amp;rsquo;re building the slide deck
and we don&amp;rsquo;t think about things like flow while we&amp;rsquo;re building it. But let&amp;rsquo;s
take a look at it as your audience will see it, one slide transitioning to the
next:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/022u2X3f3h0A/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See? Much easier to notice the text jumping around (and even the background
image gets offset a few pixels). Compare that to objects that have been properly
duplicated-in-place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/2f2s2J2p1S2b/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s super subtle and maybe no one will notice it, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a nice way
to polish your presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Your Voice</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/deliver/your-voice"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/deliver/your-voice</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You can tell a lot about a speaker by how she sounds. Is her voice wobbly?
Confident? Is she speaking too quickly? Is it one monotone delivery?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This actually matters quite a bit. It&amp;rsquo;s also one of the hardest things to
change, but improving &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; you talk is going to be one of the best things you
can do to improve your overall public speaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Variation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things the best speakers can do well is &lt;em&gt;variance of voice&lt;/em&gt;. This
encompasses a slew of different aspects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pace&lt;/strong&gt;. How fast are you speaking? By speeding up, you capture audience
attention by creating an air of excitement, of buildup. Alternatively, by
slowing down, you can assign more weight to each individual word. That&amp;rsquo;s
helpful when you&amp;rsquo;re making big, important points in your argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pitch&lt;/strong&gt;. Is your voice low or high? Variation is helpful here, particularly
in order to get an exaggerated effect (think of how you&amp;rsquo;d say &lt;em&gt;I paid FIVE
HUNDRED DOLLARS for that dinner?&lt;/em&gt;, for example).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volume&lt;/strong&gt;. Be loud, gain their attention. Be more quiet&amp;hellip; and you can still
gain their attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The point is to vary your voice when you can. You get people much more
interested in what you have to say. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing worse than having a Ben
Stein voice up on stage really early in the morning, lecturing you to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pauses&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When asked a question, Steve Jobs would frequently pause to consider the
question before answering it. As a speaker, this is one of the most frightening
things you can do: by &lt;em&gt;not talking&lt;/em&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;re immediately conscious of the fact
that &lt;em&gt;no one else is talking and everyone is waiting for what you have to say&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s completely petrifying, but it&amp;rsquo;s also incredibly effective. It makes the
audience feel like you&amp;rsquo;re really thinking something through. It&amp;rsquo;s a sign of
respect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works outside of the Q&amp;amp;A session, too: your presentation will benefit from
pauses and breaks. Nothing makes me look up from my laptop screen more than the
absense of the speaker talking. I think it&amp;rsquo;s the anticipation that does humans
in, actually: with nothing happening, humans just can&amp;rsquo;t wait until something
&lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before moving onto your next big section of your talk, take a three or five
second break. If this is uncomfortable for you — and trust me, that&amp;rsquo;s a totally
normal feeling — cheat. You can cheat by taking a sip of water. It&amp;rsquo;s the best
break in the world, and you still gain all of the benefits of taking a break
without all of the awkwardness on your end.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Writing the CFP</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/plan/writing-a-cfp"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/plan/writing-a-cfp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A lot of conferences will require you to submit a Call For Papers, or CFP, which
means you&amp;rsquo;re going to have to take this half-baked idea you have and add a bunch
of words to it even though the conference probably won&amp;rsquo;t happen until six months
from now and how the hell are you supposed to finalize this already do you know
how much can change in six months I could be dead did you think about that,
conference? I could be dead, dammit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily the conference will probably happen whether you are alive or not, so
it&amp;rsquo;s best to play by their rules and submit them a Paper, whatever that means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What is a CFP?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This goes back to academia, where people had Important Academic Papers to
disseminate amongst the intelligentsia. Compare that to your slides, which
probably have an actual picture of poop in them. We&amp;rsquo;re clearly in over our heads
already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But like the good lord says, fake it until you make it, so take a step and see
what the CFP entails. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s just a paragraph or two for your talk
abstract, a paragraph or two directly to the conference organizers, and then
maybe special things like your Social Media Network Handle so that they can be
sure the conference has lots of Social Media in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Writing the abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important thing about writing the CFP talk abstract is that this will
probably be what they put in the conference program about your talk. So that
puts you in the particularly strange situation where if you change your talk in
the subsequent few months, you might still have a really inaccurate talk
description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two things: keep it abstract, and keep it interesting. I use the &lt;em&gt;abstract&lt;/em&gt; part
of &lt;em&gt;talk abstract&lt;/em&gt; literally: I try not to include too many specific details to
give me some leeway to let the talk take me where it wants to go later when I
build it. You can&amp;rsquo;t be too amorphous to the extent where you&amp;rsquo;re not saying
anything, otherwise the organizers won&amp;rsquo;t pick it, but you can talk in more
broader themes than you would otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, keep it interesting. As I said, this will probably be in the talk program,
and if the conference you&amp;rsquo;re presenting at has multiple tracks, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to
write something interesting enough to pull people in and choose your talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Writing the note to organizers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some CFPs will let you include a quick, private note to the conference
organizers. You can put anything you want in here, but be brief (organizers are
busy, busy people), and it might be a good idea to talk more honestly about why
you think giving this talk is really important to conference attendees. That&amp;rsquo;s
really the kicker (and it should show through in your abstract as well). People
want to be moved by interesting, new perspectives, even if they don&amp;rsquo;t
necessarily agree with them at the onset. Differentiate yourself, include some
humor, and you&amp;rsquo;ll fare well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What They Don't Tell You</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/deliver/what-they-dont-tell-you-about-public-speaking"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/deliver/what-they-dont-tell-you-about-public-speaking</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Looking back on a year of speaking at conferences, I&amp;rsquo;m rather flabbergasted that
I managed to make it without my pants falling off mid-sentence or my laptop
exploding in a fireball of self-doubt and international power cords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d read all the blog posts and heard all of the advice: slow down, speak
loudly, tell a story. But goddamn, no one told me I&amp;rsquo;d have to put my laptop down
on the ground twenty feet away behind a couch because that&amp;rsquo;s the only place the
projector&amp;rsquo;s VGA cable would reach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out there&amp;rsquo;s all this other stuff to worry about, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The room isn&amp;rsquo;t your audience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re on stage in front of a few hundred people, your brain is screaming
at you &lt;strong&gt;DON&amp;rsquo;T SCREW UP IN FRONT OF ALL THESE PEOPLE&lt;/strong&gt;. But these people aren&amp;rsquo;t
your main audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Run the numbers: most technology talks are in front of 50-300 people. That&amp;rsquo;s
your most important audience; after all, they came to listen to &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;. But if
you post your talk online afterwards, you could reach thousands more. It&amp;rsquo;s a
different audience. You can choose to ignore this audience completely, or you
can choose to embrace them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most conferences are a crap shoot when it comes to video. Half the time they
won&amp;rsquo;t record your talk, and the other half of the time it may take months before
your talk is published.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something I&amp;rsquo;ve been &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/talk/git-github-secrets&quot;&gt;doing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/posts/how-github-works/&quot;&gt;recently&lt;/a&gt; is making a screen
recording of my talks using QuickTime on my Mac. It&amp;rsquo;ll record both my voice and
my slides as I flip through them. It&amp;rsquo;s a much better experience than just
posting contextless slides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Last-minute prep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of things you&amp;rsquo;ll want to take care of before jumping into
your talk:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silence your phone&lt;/strong&gt;. That means airplane mode or non-vibrate mode. You&amp;rsquo;ll
(hopefully) be getting tweets or emails mentioning you during your talk; trust
me, feeling your pants vibrate will wreck your concentration.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crank up your screen brightness&lt;/strong&gt;. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be fighting to read
your notes. You should be plugged in, anyway, so don&amp;rsquo;t worry about draining your
battery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rearrange your presenter display&lt;/strong&gt;. Rather than just mirror your slides, you
should be using a separate presenter display that shows your slide, your next
slide, a timer, your notes, and anything else you&amp;rsquo;d like to have up on-screen.
If you use Keynote, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/findouthow/iwork/#keynote09-customizepresenter&quot;&gt;customize this screen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Ground your talk in reality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve done one or two talks that I thought were great ideas initially: projects
that weren&amp;rsquo;t finished yet, things that I thought would be interesting to talk
about, and so on. They&amp;rsquo;re talks I regret. Talks should always be &lt;em&gt;reactionary&lt;/em&gt;
rather than &lt;em&gt;anticipatory&lt;/em&gt;: they&amp;rsquo;re going to come off as more natural, more
interesting, and above all, more valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about writing a detailed blog post before you speak on any subject. That
way you&amp;rsquo;ll know your comfort level with the information, and, more importantly,
you can gauge the reaction of everyone else. Is it interesting? Are you wrong?
Does anyone care?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Your talk gets interesting when it&amp;rsquo;s over&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite part about talks are the questions afterwards (if your conference
allows it). Don&amp;rsquo;t shy away from them. They&amp;rsquo;re a great barometer of how well you
know your material, and, most importantly, whether your audience &amp;ldquo;got it&amp;rdquo;. If
you plan on giving your talk again, take special note of what happens in the
question-and-answer section. It&amp;rsquo;s a goldmine for improving and changing your
talk for the next time through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Be excited&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s one mistake I consistently see made by speakers both novice and
experienced: they&amp;rsquo;re not &lt;em&gt;excited&lt;/em&gt; about their talk. Changing this one thing
will completely, utterly change the perception of your talk for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re on stage, ostensibly talking about something that interests you or makes
your life better or saves you time. &lt;strong&gt;Be fucking excited about that&lt;/strong&gt;. Let your
enthusiasm bleed through. People absolutely react to emotion. The opposite is
just as true: a passive voice on-stage will lead to a passive response by your
audience.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Typography</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/design/typography"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/design/typography</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Typography is probably the biggest thing people fuck up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look. If you&amp;rsquo;re using slides during your talk, they should &lt;em&gt;help&lt;/em&gt; you out, not
fuck everything up. I have seen more slides that look like this than I have
heard jokes about my hometown of Fargo, North Dakota (and I have literally heard
all of them, yes including your clever woodchipper joke, although yes, that one
is my favorite too):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/120u3e130u0G/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one in the room can see this- even the brown-nosers in the front row.
Remember, most projectors you&amp;rsquo;ll have to use are going to be terrible, most
people will be a minimum of 15 feet or more from you, and people at the back
could be hundreds of feet away from you. Miles, maybe. Kilomiles, for those who
use the metric system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s all that you need to know: you can&amp;rsquo;t go too big, use a ton of
contrast, don&amp;rsquo;t use many words, and choose a solid font. More than &lt;em&gt;anything
else on this entire site&lt;/em&gt;, doing those four things right will put you in the
top 10% of speakers out there. People fuck this stuff up &lt;em&gt;all the time&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t go too big&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You really can&amp;rsquo;t. I have yet to see a talk that made me think &amp;ldquo;goddamn I can&amp;rsquo;t
read this because the text is too big&amp;rdquo;. If you string together four projectors
and combine them into a mega slide you &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; can&amp;rsquo;t go big enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish more people would build their slide deck from the audience. That is, sit
in the very back of the room, hook up your laptop, and write your slides. If you
can&amp;rsquo;t see what you&amp;rsquo;re actually doing from back there, &lt;em&gt;neither can anybody
else&lt;/em&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;re at a severe advantage when you&amp;rsquo;re a foot away from your screen,
clicking away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t go big enough. Instead of this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/3x2L2w033I0G/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;you can do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/3Y1o3B0u3T3f/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you catch what I did there? It was a little subtle, but I bumped the font
size up slightly. Remove words, make it bigger. You don&amp;rsquo;t always have to take up
the entire slide, but the thing to note is that &lt;em&gt;you can&amp;rsquo;t go too big&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Use a ton of contrast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember my first example that makes me want to commit felonies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/120u3e130u0G/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dark green on black is horrible because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of contrast. This
is especially important because again, the projector you use will probably be
terrible, and the room you present in will most likely not be a pitch black
darkroom. Unless you combine a strong dark color against a strong light color,
you&amp;rsquo;re going to have a hard time getting your audience to easily see what you
wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Black and white is usually a safe combination- it&amp;rsquo;s one of those things that
it&amp;rsquo;s hard to go wrong with something so basic. And that&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; thing.
Otherwise, look into &lt;a href=&quot;/design/color/&quot;&gt;how you can select good colors&lt;/a&gt; and design
that looks a bit more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t use many words&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove words, make it bigger. It&amp;rsquo;s a good policy to have. Part of designing a
good, legible slide deck is to reduce the amount of things on your slides as
much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That does two things for you: it makes it easier for your audience to parse
(which makes it more valuable to you), and it also means less time spent reading
for your audience. That&amp;rsquo;s good for them, because no one actually wants to read
anything in life unless it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;50 Shades of Grey&lt;/em&gt;, but it&amp;rsquo;s most helpful for you,
since it means they&amp;rsquo;ll spend more time listening to you. You want your slides to
accompany your talk, not be the focal point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Choose a solid font&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of good fonts to choose. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a fairly minor thing
compared to the other three aspects discussed here, but it can make a
difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I&amp;rsquo;ll try to pick something that looks clean and obvious at large font
sizes. Sans-serifs are often good choices, although serifs can work as well&amp;hellip;
it all depends on how you use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for something a bit different than your computer&amp;rsquo;s default
fonts, try &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/fonts&quot;&gt;Google Fonts&lt;/a&gt;. They have a slew of choices
and a clever interface to help you narrow down what&amp;rsquo;s interesting to you. Other
really great sites include the &lt;a href=&quot;http://losttype.com&quot;&gt;Lost Type Co-op&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://theleagueofmoveabletype.com&quot;&gt;The
League of Moveable Type&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Slide Transitions and Animations</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/design/transitions"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/design/transitions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nah, skip &amp;lsquo;em.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except in the most subtle of cases, you&amp;rsquo;re going to look like a total moron if
you jam all these over-the-top animations in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely use the flaming fire explosion transition, though, that one is gold.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Software</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/design/software"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/design/software</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the questions I get asked a lot is: &amp;ldquo;What software did you use to make
your slides?&amp;rdquo; I reply back with: &amp;ldquo;Emacs&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just kidding, no one uses Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for you there&amp;rsquo;s only one legitimate answer to this question, and it
depends entirely on your life outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you using Windows?&lt;/strong&gt; Use &lt;a href=&quot;http://office.microsoft.com/en-us/powerpoint/&quot;&gt;PowerPoint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you using OS X?&lt;/strong&gt; Use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/iwork/keynote/&quot;&gt;Keynote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of Keynote, and it helps me create beautiful slides. But well-
designed slides have virtually nothing to do with what software creates them.
Well-designed slides are simple and clear. Those traits can be found in
Keynote, PowerPoint, MS Paint… whatever you&amp;rsquo;ve got lying around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Alternative Software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most people, Keynote and PowerPoint are going to be the traditional routes
to take. You won&amp;rsquo;t want to stray too far from this gold standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; interested in alternatives, there are plenty. Here&amp;rsquo;s a few:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/puppetlabs/showoff&quot;&gt;Showoff&lt;/a&gt; lets you write your slides in
Markdown, JavaScript, and CSS. It&amp;rsquo;s a great option if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to do
live demos of web software, particularly if you want up-to-date data or
possibly some interactivity with your audience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bartaz/impress.js&quot;&gt;impress.js&lt;/a&gt; is an option if you are
easily swayed by fancy moving animation and junk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen people type things into a plain text editor and crank up the
font size. Sometimes simple is all you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember: the clothes don&amp;rsquo;t make the (wo)man, and the software doesn&amp;rsquo;t make the
slide deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, software literally does make the slide deck, but you get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sharing Your Talk Online</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/react/sharing-your-talk-online"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/react/sharing-your-talk-online</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So there&amp;rsquo;s this thing called the internet and it&amp;rsquo;s filled with people who hate
everything you stand for and probably would like to say mean things to you (but
only on the internet and not to your face). Cool! Let&amp;rsquo;s feed the fire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Posting your slides&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you whether you want to put your slide deck online. For some people,
giving a talk is a personal thing, and they don&amp;rsquo;t want to share with people who
weren&amp;rsquo;t actually in the room with them. Makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For others, it can be interesting. Ignoring the trolls, there &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; a lot of
fine, upstanding people on the internet, and it can be a real rush to see people
having an interesting discussion based on something &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; created. It&amp;rsquo;s like the
Q&amp;amp;A session you might have had after your talk, except multiplied thousands of
times over. It can be fun to engage in these conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very basic thing you can do is put your slides on a slide sharing website
like &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com&quot;&gt;Speaker Deck&lt;/a&gt;. Depending on the talk, slides can
still be very valuable on their own, even without your voice alongside them.
After all, it&amp;rsquo;s quicker to read than it is to listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Posting your talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s helpful to go the extra distance, though. Ideally, your audience online
should get just as much context as the audience in your room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing you can do is &lt;a href=&quot;/prep/recording-your-talk&quot;&gt;record your voice&lt;/a&gt; while you
flip through your talk. You can either do this during your practice runs or, if
you want the &amp;ldquo;real deal&amp;rdquo;, record it as you give it in front of a live studio
audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, you can also get yourself recorded. A lot of conferences will take
video of their speakers nowadays, and will post it on YouTube or Vimeo or their
own sites. This is a really good approach, but just be warned: it can sometimes
take conferences months and months before they get all their video rendered and
cleaned up. It&amp;rsquo;s not trivial thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Expanding on your talk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a few intrepid souls that go even further. Rather than just try to mimic
the talk environment online, they go to greater lengths to make sure the
&lt;em&gt;online&lt;/em&gt; experience is actually the superset of experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rtomayko&quot;&gt;Ryan Tomayko&lt;/a&gt; gave a talk called
&lt;em&gt;The Shell Hater&amp;rsquo;s Handbook&lt;/em&gt;, which explained the POSIX shell to beginners.
Afterwards, he &lt;a href=&quot;http://shellhaters.heroku.com&quot;&gt;published a companion website&lt;/a&gt;
that had the video of his talk, his slide deck, and then on top of all of that,
a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tomayko.com/writings/awkward-ruby&quot;&gt;separate blog post&lt;/a&gt; that expands on
some of the things he talked about in his talk. Finally, he made a &lt;a href=&quot;http://shellhaters.heroku.com/posix&quot;&gt;reference
page&lt;/a&gt; for all the POSIX utilities you might
be interested in after all that. He created an experience that was more valuable
than just regurgitating the talk video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen people do similar things with their slide deck. They&amp;rsquo;ll split up most
of their slides into separate images, and then write a paragraph or two that
describes what was said about that particular slide. This is a lot of work
(which is the reason I haven&amp;rsquo;t quite gone that far on my own talks), but it&amp;rsquo;s
really makes a difference while reading it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want something a bit less time-consuming? Instead of just tweeting a link to
your slide deck, make a quick website and add a 4-8 paragraph introduction to
your slide deck so people get a better context of what they&amp;rsquo;re getting into.
Best bang for your buck.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Scoping out the Room</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/prep/scoping-out-the-room"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/prep/scoping-out-the-room</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For those of you about to get onto the stage in front of a million strangers for
the first time, congrats! You&amp;rsquo;re about to pee your pants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the hard work should be done by now, so you should be able to coast from
here on out lol who am I kidding things get tense at this point. There are a
couple last-minute things you should pay attention to if you have the spare
brain cells to worry about more things, though. They might make everything go a
little smoother for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day before: check the room&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t talk until the second or third day of the conference or event, you
might be able to check out the room before hand. First, sweep it for bombs and
stuff. Make sure no one&amp;rsquo;s tryna take you out. Second, just get a lay of the
land. Is your voice gonna get all echo-y? Is there a monitor on stage facing you
so you can hear yourself? How about a screen, so you can follow along with your
slides? A countdown clock, or somone in the back holding up a sign, or do you
have to monitor your time yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have access to power? What kind of microphone is it- the one you have to
hold (in which case please note it&amp;rsquo;s hard to drink a beer, hold a mic, and use a
remote all at the same time), is it a lavalier mic, or is a douchebag mic (you
know, the one that attaches to your face)?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of questions- some of them may be more interesting to you than
others. The more information you have to prep yourself, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day of: feel out the vibe&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you&amp;rsquo;re going right away, do take a minute to listen to the other speaker
and see if there&amp;rsquo;s any curveballs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s worth asking other speakers. I spoke at a conference in Norway,
and before I went up, another speaker told me that Norwegians don&amp;rsquo;t tend to
exhibit any outward emotion during a talk. I told him, &amp;ldquo;c&#39;mon dude, don&amp;rsquo;t deal
with generalizations. Plus I&amp;rsquo;m fucking hilarious so I&amp;rsquo;m sure the room will love
me.&amp;rdquo; Sure enough, it was the most excruciating fifty minute talk I&amp;rsquo;ve had to
give. Then everyone came up afterwards and said how much they enjoyed my talk. I
love that country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway broad cultural generalizations based on a single experience aside,
sometimes different rooms and different conferences react differently. A lot of
it has to do with the room, too: big, huge rooms are almost always going to be
quiet and awkward. Cram everyone into a shoebox, though, and you&amp;rsquo;re much likely
to have a more informal, fun crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Seconds before: PANIC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait no, don&amp;rsquo;t ever panic. The crowd can smell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common gotchyas that you&amp;rsquo;ll sometimes forget in the walk up to the podium: is
your microphone turned on? Do you need to plug your laptop in? Is your cell
phone turned off? (Trust me on that one.)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Repetition</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/plan/repetition"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/plan/repetition</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago I was at a conference in a Irish castle. The organizers brought
in &lt;em&gt;a storyteller&lt;/em&gt;. He wasn&amp;rsquo;t involved with the conference, he didn&amp;rsquo;t say
anything remotely related to the conference&amp;hellip; he just retold a local story that
they had been telling for generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was a remarkable speaker. You found yourself, along with everyone in the
whole room, deeply engaged in this funny, fascinating story he spun. There were
a number of reasons behind how he sucked us in, but one of those was repetition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great storytellers use repetition. Watch one of your favorite comedians. It&amp;rsquo;s
likely they&amp;rsquo;ll tell a joke at the front of the show, and then revisit a portion
of that joke later on in the show. It&amp;rsquo;s an inside joke with the audience,
really; it&amp;rsquo;s a connection on a personal level with them. &lt;em&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been through
this before, you and I.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Irish storyteller was no different. He had a recurring theme with how he
told the story, even saying the exact three or four sentences a couple different
times, only slightly changing a few words to describe the same experience for
each new character in the story we were introduced to. Then he would move on to
the next character, each time recapping that character&amp;rsquo;s story with the same few
sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Talks and storytelling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repetition is a great way to tell your story, and all talks, one way or another,
are stories. If you go back and watch a Steve Jobs keynote, virtually every
single keynote finished with a recap. There was no new information provided, but
it served as a bookend to what he was trying to convey. He also typically did
the same thing at the top of every section: he&amp;rsquo;d give you a quick few bullet
points of what he was about to talk about in greater detail. By giving people
the same information in a slightly different way, you&amp;rsquo;re giving them additional
context with which they can grab hold of the idea you&amp;rsquo;re explaining. This is
especially important when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to explain a complicated subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about using this to your advantage in your talk. Add recap sections before
you move on to the next topic. Add a final one- or two-minute closing section
that recaps everything you said. Underline and repeat important concepts one or
two times, so people know it&amp;rsquo;s important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Repeat yourself. Reiterate what you just said. Rephrase what you just said.
It&amp;rsquo;ll help persuade people to remember what you&amp;rsquo;re saying.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Remotes</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/deliver/remotes"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/deliver/remotes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A good reason to use a remote for your talk is to avoid needing to be tethered
to your laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/1h1b2Z3L0a2Y/content&quot; alt=&quot;Someone photoshop me into the Michelangelo fresco, please.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s up to you whether you want to use a remote or not. I don&amp;rsquo;t tend to move
around a lot on-stage, so I usually don&amp;rsquo;t have to stretch to reach my laptop,
but I still like using a remote because it lets me move between slides more
naturally than needing to touch my laptop every few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Remotes you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, don&amp;rsquo;t use the Apple remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/3520300d1r1O/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a great form factor, so it&amp;rsquo;s tempting, but it requires line-of-sight to
your laptop. Even if you plan on standing behind it, you won&amp;rsquo;t be lined up with
the IR receiver (and the latest MacBooks don&amp;rsquo;t even have an IR sensor either).
Every time I&amp;rsquo;ve seen someone try this it&amp;rsquo;s been a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second of all, don&amp;rsquo;t use the other Apple remote. Apple makes an app called
Keynote Remote that lets you control your slides from your iPhone. While a good
idea, it communicates over wifi or Bluetooth, which leaves yourself open to the
risk of either of those breaking on you (and it&amp;rsquo;ll happen). Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve
seen a remarkable amount of people accidentally brush their phone while they&amp;rsquo;re in the middle
of their talk and end up moving slides when they didn&amp;rsquo;t intend to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Remotes you should use&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much any other remote that has a real connection to your laptop and real buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002GHBUTU/ref=cm_sw_su_dp&quot;&gt;a Logitech remote&lt;/a&gt;
that I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of. It has simple buttons, is light and comfortable to hold,
and even has a green laser pointer available for when someone in the audience is
giving me gruff and I want to blind him in the eyeballs. Like most of these
types of remotes, it has a small USB dongle that slides out of the bottom&amp;hellip;
plug it into your laptop and it identifies as a USB keyboard so there&amp;rsquo;s no extra
software or other horsecrap to install.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re up on stage, just act normally. You just need a quick tap of a
button to go forward; no need to telegraph your button press to everyone. Don&amp;rsquo;t
forget to &lt;a href=&quot;/prep/practicing-it/&quot;&gt;practice&lt;/a&gt; with the remote, either. Even though
it&amp;rsquo;s not rocket science, you do have to get a little comfortable with it so you
don&amp;rsquo;t lose your train of thought while you&amp;rsquo;re switching slides.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Recording Your Talk</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/prep/recording-your-talk"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/prep/recording-your-talk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;re nervously up on stage in front of hundreds of strangers about to give
a talk, sweating profusely, petrified that you might get your own name wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOUNDS LIKE A GOOD TIME TO RECORD YOUR WEAKNESS AND UNCERTAINTY!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/posts/what-they-dont-tell-you-about-public-speaking/&quot;&gt;What They Don&amp;rsquo;t Tell You About Public Speaking&lt;/a&gt;
post, I got a number of questions asking about how I record the audio and slide
transitions of my talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;QuickTime on OS X&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a million ways to do this. Keynote, for example, has a recording
function built directly into presenter mode, although it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to tweak
and to export. Beyond that, there&amp;rsquo;s a million different apps you can use to do
this, too. I try to stay as simple as possible: on my Mac, I just use
QuickTime&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Screen Recording&lt;/em&gt; feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either before a talk on-stage or at home practicing my slides, running a quick
screen recording session is pretty simple. Start a new Screen Recording:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/0X2J3q3V3r04/content&quot; alt=&quot;Screen Recording&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;then hit record:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/1b1A0R1a0i3r/content&quot; alt=&quot;Record&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re on stage and on a projector, the trick is to get QuickTime to record
your &lt;em&gt;projected slides&lt;/em&gt; rather than your presenter display. Luckily, QuickTime
makes it really easy. Before you start your slideshow, hit record, then mouse
over to the other screen (in other words, the projector). It&amp;rsquo;ll dim the screen
and inform you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/3w2K2e3d0d3r2s2Y1X0f/content&quot; alt=&quot;Click to Record&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click it, then you&amp;rsquo;re off to the races. It&amp;rsquo;ll record your voice on your internal
microphone (surprisingly well, too), and as you flip through your slides it&amp;rsquo;ll
retain all the transitions and little details you can&amp;rsquo;t get from viewing slides
online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s for you&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about recording your talks is that it&amp;rsquo;s a great learning tool.
It&amp;rsquo;s cliché, but force yourself to listen to yourself. It will &lt;strong&gt;utterly change
your perspective&lt;/strong&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll hear all of the &lt;em&gt;uhhhhh&lt;/em&gt;s and &lt;em&gt;ummmmm&lt;/em&gt;s you didn&amp;rsquo;t
notice at the time. That&amp;rsquo;s good; listening to yourself talk is designed to make
you angry enough to change those habits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s for them&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned previously, your mileage may vary when it comes to conference
videos of your talks. Half of conferences won&amp;rsquo;t film you, and the other half may
take months to publish all their talks while organizers take a well-deserved
breather post-conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So think about recording your own talk so you can post it on your site
immediately after your talk. If you&amp;rsquo;ve wowed someone in the room, they&amp;rsquo;ll be
able to share the experience of your talk to their friends as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/holman&quot;&gt;my screencasts and talks&lt;/a&gt;
because they&amp;rsquo;re a swell company.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Practicing It</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/prep/practicing-it"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/prep/practicing-it</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do you know how Steve Jobs sounded so confident when he gave his famous Apple
keynotes? The answer is pretty obvious: he was a huge, huge cocaine fiend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/0f37101j3D3u/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the rest of us, there&amp;rsquo;s practicing. Did you know that practice makes
perfect? Because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. That was a filthy lie. But it does help out a ton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How to practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, everyone&amp;rsquo;s different, but here&amp;rsquo;s how I do it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I get the whole slide deck in a &amp;ldquo;finished&amp;rdquo; state. &amp;ldquo;Finished&amp;rdquo; instead of
finished because it&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much you&amp;rsquo;ll change after you&amp;rsquo;ve gone through
your talk aloud once or twice. It becomes pretty obvious what works and what
doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I&amp;rsquo;m ready, I go through the talk two or three times, all the way through.
Primarily I&amp;rsquo;m looking for 1) how it feels altogether, and 2) how long it takes
to get through the whole thing. Because of the latter, it&amp;rsquo;s important to &lt;em&gt;say
words out loud&lt;/em&gt; while practicing. You speak in your mind way too quickly, and
you need to teach yourself the muscle memory of how your talk fits together in
your mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a strange last sentence but we&amp;rsquo;ll go with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two or three times isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of go-throughs- if you&amp;rsquo;re a beginner and you&amp;rsquo;re
nervous about it, I&amp;rsquo;d definitely do more like five or seven. Part of what helps
me, though, is that I&amp;rsquo;m constantly talking to myself about the talk over the
week or so that I&amp;rsquo;m building it. By the time I&amp;rsquo;m up on stage, I&amp;rsquo;ve probably at
least thought about every slide a dozen times. By thinking about it that much,
it lets me be a little looser on stage and ad-lib more parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When to practice&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like everything with public speaking, you should give yourself as much time to
practice as you can. But like everything with public speaking, you&amp;rsquo;re going to
wait until the night before, aren&amp;rsquo;t you. You are such a jerk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, though, try not to push it back &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; much. Sometimes you do run into
times where you want to redo entire parts of the deck after hearing it out loud
and realizing you sound stupid. That&amp;rsquo;s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Recording&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People say you should record yourself talking, and they&amp;rsquo;re a hundred percent
correct. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe how stupid you sound when you&amp;rsquo;re listening to
yourself later. All the &lt;em&gt;umms&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;ahhs&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;likes&lt;/em&gt; sneak in that you never
noticed previously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t given a talk before, definitely try &lt;a href=&quot;/prep/recording-your-talk&quot;&gt;recording
yourself&lt;/a&gt; before you give it for real. It&amp;rsquo;ll be the
best thing you do — I guarantee it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Number of Slides</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/plan/number-of-slides"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/plan/number-of-slides</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the grimy sweat dripping off a brow as the speaker punishes three
hundred slides in a half hour. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the off-the-cuff confidence of a
speaker give her talk without even using a single slide. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a friend eat
three Kentucky Fried Chicken Double Down™ sandwiches. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen things, man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People keep focusing on this weird metric. They always ask me &amp;ldquo;well how many
slides do you have left?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s an irrelevant question, though, because the
number of slides you should plan for ultimately depends on the type of talk you
want to give and the type of person you are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;A good first step&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll understand yourself more as you give more talks. As you
&lt;a href=&quot;/prep/practicing-it&quot;&gt;practice&lt;/a&gt; more and more, you start understanding how many
slides you need in order to comfortably get your point across. If this is your
first talk, that might be a bit difficult to judge, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I go a bit heavier on the slides than most people. Slides are the
outline for me: I don&amp;rsquo;t put that many words on a slide, because I only need a
little push in order for me to remember what I wanted to talk about. Since I
only use one or two words per slide, I tend to flip through them a bit quicker
than many other presenters. That ends up generating maybe a hundred slides or so
for a thirty-minute talk, for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that can change depending on the talk. If it&amp;rsquo;s less technical, if it&amp;rsquo;s more
of a story, you can get by with only a couple slides (or no slides at all!) With
a less-technical focus, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to put as much jargon on the screen, and
that lets you play with the pace and tempo as you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Timing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s really no way to easily judge how quickly you&amp;rsquo;re going to go through
slides. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll find myself doing ten slides in twenty seconds, if I&amp;rsquo;m
trying to convey a rushed, more intensive moment (possibly for humor-related
purposes). Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll sit on a slide for five or ten minutes, if the slide
warrants it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to timing, it resides entirely on you: how fast your cadence is,
how much you drift off-tangent, and so on. If you&amp;rsquo;re new to public speaking, the
best thing you can do for yourself is to start practicing it before you even
finish the entire slide deck, so you have a better handle on how much time
you&amp;rsquo;ll need to devote on making more slides.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dealing with Nervousness</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/deliver/nervousness"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/deliver/nervousness</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know of anyone who does a lot of public speaking and doesn&amp;rsquo;t still get
nervous every time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about this to someone whose talks I greatly admire. He has a certain
confidence and ease onstage and in person that makes it hard to believe he has a
hard time with nervousness. I asked him about it and he admitted he can&amp;rsquo;t eat
anything before he gives his talk. Even if he has a closing keynote at 5pm, then
6pm will be the first food he eats that day. Everyone is nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with nerves&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nervousness impacts people differently. Whenever I&amp;rsquo;d play a solo during high
school jazz band, I&amp;rsquo;d sometimes start yawning. That&amp;rsquo;s just how I coped: I get
very sleepy physically, probably as some defense to hide behind an external
barrier of nonchalance (meanwhile inside my head I was losing it). I didn&amp;rsquo;t even
realize it at first: my director noticed during rehearsal once and said &amp;ldquo;look at
him, he&amp;rsquo;s yawning!&amp;rdquo; which, if you&amp;rsquo;re an aspiring high school jazz band director
take note, is a &lt;em&gt;horrible&lt;/em&gt; thing to say to someone who is already very nervous
and now has to worry about not yawning of all things, sheesh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nerves are a good thing, though, and if there&amp;rsquo;s anything I&amp;rsquo;ve learned it&amp;rsquo;s that
they do help you out. Many times they serve to put you on edge. My brain tends
to work much more quickly — and &lt;em&gt;better&lt;/em&gt; — when I&amp;rsquo;m nervous and on stage
(admittedly I think it takes some experience before nerves turn into an
advantage like that). Realizing that nervousness is a feeling designed to &lt;em&gt;help&lt;/em&gt;
you rather than &lt;em&gt;hurt&lt;/em&gt; you is a great first step. If you weren&amp;rsquo;t nervous, it
means that you don&amp;rsquo;t care about what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen. If you don&amp;rsquo;t care, then
get off the fucking stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practice is the number one remedy, of course. Rehearsing is the practice of
reducing the amount of unknown in your life. You become more accustomed with
what you have to say, you expand your context around just the lines you planned
to say verbatim. You become more confident with ad libbing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Exponential decay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know how I said everyone gets nervous? That&amp;rsquo;s true&amp;hellip; to an extent. I&amp;rsquo;ve
given a lot of talks over the last few years, and while the nervousness doesn&amp;rsquo;t
ever go away, the &lt;em&gt;duration&lt;/em&gt; of the nervousness does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first few talks I gave, I was nervous from the first slide all the way
to the last slide. Every step was stressful. But as I gave more talks I realized
that it quickly started to halve. I&amp;rsquo;d make it halfway through before I&amp;rsquo;d get a
bit more confident. Then a quarter of the way. Now it&amp;rsquo;s to the point where I
really only face the major portions of nervousness during the first few minutes
of a talk. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure it&amp;rsquo;s ever going to get better than that (and I still
haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out a way to reduce the nerves in the hours and days during the
lead-up to the talk), but realizing that I was getting better at it was a pretty
huge comfort. As with everything, if you do it enough times you just become more
comfortable with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are ways you can cheat this process along, too. At my company we encourage
people to give run-throughs of their talks before they actually have to do it.
This is designed to be as realistic as possible, complete with projector and
podium and butts in seats. If you mess up, your coworkers will be nice about it
and will give you feedback at the end. Just getting you up on stage in front of
people — &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; people, even if they are your friends — is going to help cheat
the process along. You get a little bit more comfortable with every step you
take.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Live Tech Demos</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/prep/live-demos"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/prep/live-demos</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Live demos are like Global Thermonuclear War: the only way to win is to not do a
live demo in front of hundreds of strangers in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you want to show off a new software library that you wrote, or a neat
feature of a language you just discovered. Live demos — where someone flips away
from their prepared deck to show how to use something — are notoriously
failure-prone. As an audience member, you brace yourself as you go from a
prepared haven to the wild west of demoing software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can be done, and they can be done well, but it&amp;rsquo;s likely that you will not
do it well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Faking it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there are a number of ways to fake a live demo. One is to take a
screencast of yourself performing all of the commands and then you play back
that video in front of your audience. This has the benefit of being able to
embed the video directly into your presentation deck, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to flip
between apps and display mirroring (which is always going to be a pain in the
butt to watch).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find this approach pretty great, as you don&amp;rsquo;t have to stress about what you&amp;rsquo;re
typing and can focus entirely on providing the commentary. You can also
pre-record the commentary too, if that makes you more comfortable, although be
sure not to overdo it since before long you&amp;rsquo;re basically just playing a movie
for people and that&amp;rsquo;s no fun for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also do a live demo, but with a &amp;ldquo;script&amp;rdquo; — in other words, literally
have a text document that you copy and paste commands from, if you&amp;rsquo;re
demonstrating a CLI. While watching a demo, I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly care about
whether someone is typing something in real-time, and copying from a script
ensures you won&amp;rsquo;t make any typos.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Improving a Talk</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/react/improving"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/react/improving</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;That wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad. You&amp;rsquo;re all done with your talk and everything went great!
Or they went terrible and no one likes you, but you are somewhat reasonable
about it and maintain that you will improve next time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed giving a talk, chances are that you might want to give that same
talk again sometime. There are a lot of conferences out there, it&amp;rsquo;s normal to
repeat the same talk a couple of different times to different audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s no reason you can&amp;rsquo;t improve the talk, though. Next time could be even
better! Or at least, less horrible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Pay attention&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest thing you should do is pay attention during your talk. Are people
not listening to you? Are they on their laptops or phones? Do they seem like
they&amp;rsquo;re a little tuned out? Those are good signs that you may want to improve
that section of the talk. Either go slower if it&amp;rsquo;s a little too complicated, or
make it more interesting if it&amp;rsquo;s a little too boring, or drop the entire section
if it&amp;rsquo;s just not that interesting. Sometimes you have to give a talk a couple of
times before you can make a final value judgement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one thing you should pay attention to is the
&lt;a href=&quot;/react/handling-questions/&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt; session of your talk, if you have one. What
are people asking you about? That&amp;rsquo;s a huge sign that they&amp;rsquo;re either really
interested in that portion of your talk or they&amp;rsquo;re really confused about it
still. It could also mean you did a poor job at arguing that aspect and they
still don&amp;rsquo;t quite believe you, which means that&amp;rsquo;s a great place to start
reworking and improving to clarify your point better. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have any
official Q&amp;amp;A, ask people in the hallways and at any meetups later that night.
It&amp;rsquo;s also a more informal environment, so people will go into their thoughts a
bit more than they would in front of an entire room of people.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Handling Questions</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/react/handling-questions"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/react/handling-questions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You survived your talk. Congratulations! Every now and then a head of state gets
assassinated during their speech, so pat yourself on your back: you&amp;rsquo;re already
better off than those unfortunate souls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t crack that bottle of tequila open yet, though. If you&amp;rsquo;re at a conference,
or definitely if you&amp;rsquo;re giving a presentation to coworkers, you might have to
face your gravest challenge yet: the question and answer section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I love Q&amp;amp;A. I&amp;rsquo;d rather give five minute talks and hour long Q&amp;amp;A
sessions, but then again I also don&amp;rsquo;t mind eating the cheese straight out of the
pouch in the Velveeta Mac and Cheese box, so your mileage may vary. Q&amp;amp;A can be a
lot of fun because you&amp;rsquo;re directly talking about things people care about, and
it helps you gauge what people are interested in in case you&amp;rsquo;re giving this talk
again later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s always some shit you have to deal with, though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with not understanding a question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New speakers freak out about Q&amp;amp;A for a number of odd reasons, but the main thing
you&amp;rsquo;ll end up worrying about? Not understanding what the hell you&amp;rsquo;re being
asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re up in front of everyone. Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;re in the spotlight, which makes
it hard to see who&amp;rsquo;s asking the question. Sometimes the person asking the
question doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a microphone. Sometimes the person asking the question has
a heavy accent or isn&amp;rsquo;t a native speaker. Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;re just stressed out
from your talk that your fried brain won&amp;rsquo;t have the faintest idea of what the
questioner is talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of these things the same rules always apply. They all sound stupid,
now, while you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be amazed about what you&amp;rsquo;ll forget
when you&amp;rsquo;re on-stage after a talk. The rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask them to repeat the question&lt;/strong&gt;. The easiest and simplest thing. Usually
if you can&amp;rsquo;t hear the question, it&amp;rsquo;s almost certain the audience can&amp;rsquo;t, either
(which is a good reason to repeat the question, too). Repeating the question
doesn&amp;rsquo;t make you look like a douche: it makes you look like someone who cares
enough to get it right or, heaven forbid, someone who just didn&amp;rsquo;t catch the
question the first time around.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have them ask you privately afterwards&lt;/strong&gt;. Still don&amp;rsquo;t have the foggiest idea
of what&amp;rsquo;s going on? Just ask them to chat with you after. It lets you talk to
them in more detail, and it&amp;rsquo;s perfectly fine not to bother the rest of the
audience with more back-and-forth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with fucking up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after all the prep in the world, sometimes you fuck up. You say something
you didn&amp;rsquo;t intend, or you&amp;rsquo;re just wrong about something. There&amp;rsquo;s always going to
be someone in the audience who will try to correct you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If what they&amp;rsquo;re saying sounds right, or you&amp;rsquo;re not sure what&amp;rsquo;s true and what&amp;rsquo;s
false anymore, just cop up to it. &amp;ldquo;Whoa, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that&amp;rdquo; is a big
concession, and it makes you look like someone open to new ideas. It&amp;rsquo;s not bad
to be a flip flopper. Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;re just going to be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with questions that aren&amp;rsquo;t questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This almost always happens at least once at every conference I&amp;rsquo;ve been at. You
know the type: the dude in the back who&amp;rsquo;s already 75 seconds into his &amp;ldquo;question&amp;rdquo;
and yet you still haven&amp;rsquo;t heard anything remotely close to what could be
considered a question in fact you&amp;rsquo;re pretty sure this smug jerkhole doesn&amp;rsquo;t have
a question and you mostly just want to punch him in the ever-flapping mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snap out of it. You have a microphone. Use it. &lt;em&gt;Do you have an actual
question?&lt;/em&gt;, when said properly, is probably the funniest thing for the rest of
the audience to hear ever. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a jerk about it: just ask them
if they&amp;rsquo;re going to get to the point. If you&amp;rsquo;re irritated, I guarantee the rest
of the audience is a heartbeat away from mob justice themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just be nice and you&amp;rsquo;re going to be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Dealing with assholes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re really not going to run into assholes very often. People worry about the
rogue troll in the audience, but typically human beings are pretty timid,
respectful creatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, though, someone may challenge what you said in a rude
manner. Again, remember that you have the mic, and more importantly, you are
literally in a position of power: you&amp;rsquo;re up on stage, under the lights, in front
of the room, whatever. Stay classy and you&amp;rsquo;re going to win the argument. You
return the snideness back at them and you&amp;rsquo;ve lost the battle of public opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When in doubt, defuse, concede some ground as a good-natured way of letting the
jerk feel like they&amp;rsquo;ve won something, and move on to the next question. In a
conference, organizers will likely help you with this, as they&amp;rsquo;ll want to avoid
confrontation too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re not trying to win over the asshole; who wants another asshole, anyway?
You&amp;rsquo;re fighting to make everyone else in the room think to themselves &amp;ldquo;god I
don&amp;rsquo;t even care about this anymore, fuck this weirdo HE STILL HASN&amp;rsquo;T EVEN ASKED
A QUESTION YET&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t pick a battle with someone who buys ink by the barrel, and don&amp;rsquo;t pick a
battle with someone who&amp;rsquo;s up on stage and who has been talking for awhile. You
have all the power, and you&amp;rsquo;ll win anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Fucking up</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/deliver/fucking-up"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/deliver/fucking-up</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At some point or another, the probability of fucking up in front of a lot of
strangers you don&amp;rsquo;t know approaches one. It&amp;rsquo;s going to happen. You&amp;rsquo;re going to
say something you didn&amp;rsquo;t mean. You&amp;rsquo;re going to blankly stare at your screen when
you forget the argument that you&amp;rsquo;ve never, ever had problems remembering before.
You&amp;rsquo;re going to accidentally horribly insult someone, and it was the last
possible thing you meant to do. These things happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;People don&amp;rsquo;t care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you recognize this by now. Most people in life don&amp;rsquo;t care about you or
what you have to say. This goes tenfold for a conference. Most attendees will be
bored and will likely be on their laptop anyway. It&amp;rsquo;s a harsh world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s cool. That&amp;rsquo;s the number one comfort you can usually rely on. Even if you
find something you said to be glaringly horrifying, chances are &lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not that
big of a deal to them&lt;/em&gt;. Again, this is obvious, but it bears repeating: you&amp;rsquo;re
probably going to be fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing you can do is not draw attention to your gaffe and just move on.
I&amp;rsquo;ve certainly found myself in the middle of stories that were irrelevant, too
long, and boring as rocks. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s best to cut your losses and say &amp;ldquo;and
wow, this story is stupid, boy am I sorry&amp;rdquo; and move on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Stay humble&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most things when you&amp;rsquo;re on stage, staying humble is a good quality to
have. You&amp;rsquo;re pretty exposed, and if you mess up, well, just be honest. If
something obvious happened that you can&amp;rsquo;t sweep under the rug easily, put your
hat in your hand and say &amp;ldquo;wow, I did not mean to say that&amp;hellip; sorry!&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;crap,
totally blew my train of thought- let&amp;rsquo;s circle back on that&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Have an out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good approach is to always have an out so you minimize the chance of mistakes.
Practicing your talk over and over is great, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to be
strategic, when you can. Usually I try to do a minute or two at the start of my
talks and improv a small joke or tell a funny 30 second story, just to get
people interested. If I&amp;rsquo;m really nervous about losing my place, that&amp;rsquo;s why I
have presenter&amp;rsquo;s notes. Or notecards. Or even slides. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason you
can&amp;rsquo;t use all these things to your advantage to make it less likely you&amp;rsquo;ll mess
up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dimensions</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/design/dimensions"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/design/dimensions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s agonizing to try to come up with a joke about what dimensions your slides
should be. Just agonizing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Projectors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your smartphone in your pocket has greater processing power than the computer
that sent humans to the moon in 1969, but every single projector you will ever
touch is basically just puking twelve pixels up on the wall and calling it a
day. Projectors suck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of conferences and meeting rooms you will present in will have
really low-fidelity projectors. Don&amp;rsquo;t bank on projecting on a fancy, bright,
widescreen projector; you&amp;rsquo;re more than likely going to be disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;4:3 or widescreen?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should you present in widescreen or the more traditional 4:3 aspect ratio?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve switched to writing all new slides as widescreen. It makes your slides look
more cinematic, which I would argue feels more polished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major concern here is how those slides will work on an older projector.
Keynote in particular does a great job at scaling your slides. I haven&amp;rsquo;t
experienced a problem on any projector since I started this; 4:3 aspect ratio
projectors simply show my slides with black bars on the top and bottom, which is
reasonable and preserves the cinematic feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Resolution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tend to opt for bigger slides: 1920x1080. That gives me full 1080p resolution,
so if I ever &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; end up presenting on a nice, modern projector, my slides will
really pop. You can always scale down high-resolution slides, but it&amp;rsquo;s much
harder to scale them up.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Color</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/design/color"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/design/color</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you wrap your hands around your neck long enough, your face is probably going
to change color. If you keep them there too long, then your face is going to
die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colors are important in slides, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Identity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colors are all pretty to look at and junk, but they serve a real purpose: with
smart usage of color, you can make it easier for your audience to follow you
around as you jump from slide to slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing a great color palette for your talk can help you visually break out
different sections, underline recap areas, and overall make your presentation
look, well, presentable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Finding colors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re like me (and for that I sincerely apologize), you probably haven&amp;rsquo;t the
faintest idea of how to come up with colors that look great together. Don&amp;rsquo;t
worry: you can cheat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Head to a place like COLOURlovers and look at their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.colourlovers.com/palettes&quot;&gt;color
palettes&lt;/a&gt;. They have millions. Browse
around and find something that tickles your fancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/3P3o2D073j1s/content&quot; alt=&quot;This one looks nice&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually I look for bright colors that go well on projectors. That means colors
with a lot of contrast. For example, choose a dark, a light, and an accent. That
way you can layer the dark on the light and still read it from in the way back
of the room you&amp;rsquo;re giving the talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Importing colors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve found the colors you want, you&amp;rsquo;ll want to get them into your slide
deck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Keynote, you can hold &lt;code&gt;⇧Shift + ⌘ + C&lt;/code&gt; to open up the Colors palette. Click
the magnifying glass and you can suck your selected color into your slide deck.
In the third tab of this panel, though, you can create a new palette. This is
usually where I stash all of my colors for the talk so it&amp;rsquo;s readily at hand for
later:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/0W1u1B3b0o44/content&quot; alt=&quot;Color palette&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Using colors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to be conscious about how you use colors. I usually try to use them to break
up different sections of my talk (see this post about
&lt;a href=&quot;/plan/an-outline/&quot;&gt;Outlining&lt;/a&gt; for more about sections). In &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/talk/product-is-the-byproduct/&quot;&gt;The Product is the
Byproduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, I used bright
white slides to denote new sections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/2e3J0e413E1X/content&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is also great for &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt;, too. In this case, I get a nice clean white screen
that&amp;rsquo;s visually different enough for me to realize &amp;ldquo;Okay. I hit a new section. I
can take a sip of water, I can take a breath, I can let people catch up.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, I&amp;rsquo;ll also usually offset the colors in the introduction and the
closing. If you&amp;rsquo;re using bright orange the entire talk and you suddenly hit four
white slides in a row, it starts to feel different, like the natural close of
your talk. Use that to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Outlining</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/plan/an-outline"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/plan/an-outline</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Usually I&amp;rsquo;ll come up with a great idea, like &lt;em&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to reveal
to the entire world that 2Pac is still alive and working at a San Francisco
startup&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So then I have this great talk idea, but then I&amp;rsquo;m stuck facing the music: how
the hell do I flesh this into &lt;em&gt;an entire talk&lt;/em&gt;? There&amp;rsquo;s all these subtleties to
cover, like should I talk about how &lt;em&gt;2 of Amerikaz Most Wanted&lt;/em&gt; was actually an
allegory for his desire to work at a quiet Silicon Valley startup job for the
rest of his life? Or maybe I should bring up his deeply suspect tattoo:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/1i2E0h0N0m2k/content&quot; alt=&quot;Is Path a money laundering front for Tupac Shakur? Teach the controversy.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In either case, I almost always tackle a new talk by &lt;strong&gt;outlining first&lt;/strong&gt;. There
are a million different ways to do this, so your mileage may vary, but this is
what&amp;rsquo;s worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Inside Outlining&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do something I&amp;rsquo;d like to call &lt;em&gt;inside outlining&lt;/em&gt;, because it&amp;rsquo;s kind of a fun
play on words and by inventing new terminology you can eventually ask for
royalties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, write the &lt;em&gt;important things first&lt;/em&gt;. These should be your main
sections that are meaty enough to dive into greater detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It depends on the talk, but I think generally most talks are best served if you
can deliver them in three sections. It&amp;rsquo;s limiting, to be sure, but it creates a
much more cohesive narrative if you can lay down your main argument with three
distinct sections, each with supporting details. So, for this Pac talk, I&amp;rsquo;d
start out with these five bullets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section one: 2Pac loves the Bay Area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section two: Possible connections to the tech industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section three: He lives in my basement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outro&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Really avoid trying to flesh out this outline past this point, even if you want
to. It&amp;rsquo;s good to sit on this for a little bit before getting too deep down the
rabbit hole. Let it sink in and get a feel for whether you&amp;rsquo;re happy with this
main foundation of your talk. If you&amp;rsquo;re not, then change it. If you want to add
or remove more main sections, go for it: there are no rules in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rule number two: start fleshing out the outline. This is where the &amp;ldquo;inside
outlining&amp;rdquo; comes into play, for me. I never really finish each point one-by-one.
I sort of add one or two supporting points to each main point. Something like
this (ignoring the intro and outro):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2Pac loves the Bay Area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possible connections to the tech industry

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Path tattoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He lives in my basement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;then a couple more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2Pac loves the Bay Area

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lived in Marin City for years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possible connections to the tech industry

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Path tattoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He lives in my basement

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No really, I have photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As you get a better handle for the overall flow, you can start diving into more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2Pac loves the Bay Area

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lived in Marin City for years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oaktown, Oakland definitely in the house&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possible connections to the tech industry

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Path tattoo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;White Man&#39;z World&lt;/em&gt; (1996)

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearly a metaphor for today&amp;rsquo;s tech industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He lives in my basement

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No really, I have photos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For me, I tend to keep these outlines very short and high-level. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t
get much further than three tiers: top tier is the slide introduction to the
section, the second bullet level is a slide and large point inside that section,
and the third level of bullets tend to translate to multiple slides supporting
the #2 level of points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in seeing this in practice? &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/holman/80f254b91d2d414d447f&quot;&gt;Here is my raw
outline&lt;/a&gt; for my &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zachholman.com/talk/how-github-no-longer-works/&quot;&gt;How
GitHub (no longer)
Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; talk. Those
twenty-some lines generated 141 slides. For me, I just use an outline as a point
to channel my thoughts, &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; as the verbatim bible of my talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time I only use about half of my outline in my actual talk&amp;hellip;
sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s just a springboard. That&amp;rsquo;s what works for me. And that&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s
important for you, too: getting your thoughts converted to slides is hard
enough, so try a few things out and find out what works for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Idea</title>
   <link href="http://speaking.io/plan/an-idea"/>
   <updated>2014-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
   <id>http://speaking.io/plan/an-idea</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s easy. You know that you&amp;rsquo;re the world&amp;rsquo;s foremost expert on the
brands of toothbrushes that Sinéad O&#39;Connor used between 1988 and 1991. You know
that you can create a talk about her toothcare that is so poignant that it will
fundamentally make us rethink our station in life. You want to do this talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cl.ly/image/342n3r3y3B1X/content&quot; alt=&quot;sinead o&#39;teeth&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What if it&amp;rsquo;s not that easy? What if you&amp;rsquo;re not some eclectic expert on
something? You&amp;rsquo;re interested in giving a talk, but what should you talk about?
It can be a little daunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all — and say this with me — most speakers are pretty stupid. Really!
They&amp;rsquo;re no more special than you or me. They just have the advantage in two
areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They&amp;rsquo;ve done this particular something a lot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They want to talk about it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it. And that can be you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Keep the focus small&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part is that you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; be an expert in most things. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to
give a talk that encompasses the entirety of the human condition: instead, focus
on something really, really, really small and start learning everything you can
about it. Your talk doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to recap everything you&amp;rsquo;ve ever learned in your
life; you can spend a few weeks looking at a small aspect of something that
interests you and talk about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more, &lt;em&gt;you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have to be an expert&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve sat through
hundreds of talks from &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; that were boring and terrible to live through.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also listened to beginners talk about subject matter that I knew very well,
but it was &lt;em&gt;still interesting&lt;/em&gt; to me because it made me rethink with fresh eyes
something that I had thought I had known all about. That&amp;rsquo;s really what it&amp;rsquo;s all
about: making your audience reconsider their own perspectives. You don&amp;rsquo;t have to
be smarter than them or even be more correct than them to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What tickles your fancy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to avoid starting with something you know nothing about. It&amp;rsquo;ll bite you.
Instead, as you might expect, start with something that fascinates you. It
serves as a good foundation for future learning on the subject (and you most
certainly will learn as you build your talk: when it&amp;rsquo;s your ass on stage, you
find yourself working hard to avoid potential embarassment if you can avoid it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to have a little bit extra, too. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to be stretching your
time while you&amp;rsquo;re up on stage, because with nerves and fast talking you&amp;rsquo;ll
probably end up under time anyway. You want to find a subject to talk about that
is a little meaty, so that even if you can&amp;rsquo;t cover quite everything in your
talk, you can go over it in more detail in &lt;a href=&quot;/react/handling-questions/&quot;&gt;Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
